[Music]
hello Internet I am Rd lady and in this
tutorial I'm going to show you how to
extract 3D models from PlayStation 2
games in the previous part of this
tutorial I have shown you how to extract
the textures and now let's extract the
3D models all the 3D models extract from
PlayStation 2 come with a lot of
problems right after they are extracted
so I'm going to also show here how to
solve all these problems that you may
find when you extract 3D models from
PlayStation 2 games and for extracting
the models we're going to use the
pcsx2 it's a Playstation 2 emulator that
I have shown you how to download and set
up in the previous part of this tutorial
so let's open this emulator and let's
change its plug-in settings so we can
extract the 3D models so let's go in
config video and plug-in
settings and let's change the renderer
to direct
3d9 software if we use direct 3d9
Hardware the model extraction is not
going to work now we just have to click
in okay and then we're going to run the
game
and now we're going to skip the game
until a scene that has the models that
we want to
extract now that I reached a scene where
are the models that I want to extract
now I just have to hold shift and press
f8 to extract all the models in this
scene once I hold shift and press f8 all
the 3D models from this scene were
generated and exported to the snap
folder inside the emulator folder but
all these models that we have just
extracted they're going to have a
distortion problem this Distortion
problem that I'm showing right now is
going to happen to all the models
extracted because of the way that the
PlayStation 2 emulators process the
three-dimensional vectors in the scam
and to fix this Distortion problem we're
going to use the PCS X2 model converter
so let's download and copy this model
converted to the same folder where are
the extracted models
so now let's run this model converter
and here we have to specify the
dimensions of the screenshot of the game
scene that was taken automatically by
the Playstation 2 emulator generated
automatically in the same place where
our models were generated so to discover
the dimensions of the screenshot we just
have to go in the file properties and
copy the height and width
[Music]
numbers we also have to disable the
remove faces outside the screen option
otherwise all the bottom part of lion's
body body is going to be deleted because
it was not showing up in the screen when
we extracted the models and after that
we just have to clicking
process we can see that a new file was
created in the same folder where are the
extracted
models and now we just have to click in
the repair mesh Tab and after that we
finally click in this process button
after the process is done the model
converted will have generated another
file and this is the file that we're
going to import in 3ds Max so let's go
to 3ds
Max here in 3ds Max we go to the menu we
click import and then we select the file
that ends with the mes fixed suffix
which was the last file generated by the
model
converter once we open this file we can
see that all the models of the game
scene were imported together in one
object so we're going to have to remove
all these models that we don't want and
keep just the model of interest but
before cleaning up this scene we're
going to have to fix a problem when we
imported all the 3D models to this scene
somehow the X Y and Z arrows the Gizmo
got totally displaced it's far away from
the center of the 3D models where it
should be so let's fix this mistake in
the XYZ arrows first and then we're
going to be able to manipulate these 3D
models more easily so to fix this
problem first we have to click in the
hierarch key Tab and then we need to
enable the effect pivot only button this
button will allow us to move the XYZ
arrows without moving the 3D model so
now that we activated this button we can
adjust the placement of the XYZ arrows
and move it to the center of the 3D
models
[Music]
now to clean up all the undesired models
in this scene we have to go to the
modify tab then we click in the editable
mesh and then we have to activate the
element selector by clicking in the
element
[Music]
icon so now we can select all the models
that we don't want and we can remove
them from the scene an easy way to do
this is to select the model of Interest
the model that we want to keep and then
we go to the edit menu and then we click
in select invert and now we can press
delete or go to the edit menu again
again and click in delete so by doing
this we have removed all the models that
we don't want there is still some faces
or polygons here that we don't want so
we can just select one by one of them
and delete
them if the XY Z arrows get displaced
again we can do the same thing once
again to fix this problem you just have
to go to the higher kit tab enable the
same button again and then you just have
to displace the XYZ arrows to the
desired
[Applause]
location after that we can use the
resize tool so we can change the width
and height of the
[Music]
model if you want to put this 3D model
index exact center of the animation and
modeling scene you can use the select
and move tool to select the 3D model and
then you just have to type zero in the X
Y and Z dimensions of the 3D
model now that our model is in the
center of our scam we can use again the
resize tool to increase the size of our
model
[Music]
if the 3D model still has a little bit
of distortion even after resizing it in
the end of this video I'm going to show
you a modifier that can fix this problem
and here's a problem that always happens
with all the models that are extracted
using PCS X2 the direction of all the
faces or the normals of many faces get
randomly displaced we can see here some
faces that are black or transparent
depending on how we Zoom or place the
camera and for fixing this problem we
have to export this 3D model in obj
format but but here in the exporting
options we have to enable the texture
coordinates but we have to disable the
normals so all the normals of this model
all the orientation of the faces is
going to be reset the other options we
can leave here as default and now you
just have to click in
export now let's reset our scene and
let's import the 3D model that we have
just
[Music]
exported the new imported model will
show up here in the middle of the scene
but it will be very small again so we
can use the scaling tool to increase the
size of this 3D model again
[Music]
[Applause]
you can see now that the problem with
the face
orientation was fixed the problem with
the faces orientation was fixed but we
still have another problem to solve we
have to to decrease the size of the
normal indicator and for doing this we
have to go to the modify Tab and then we
have to enable the polygon selector by
clicking in the polygon icon and now you
just have to press control a to select
all the polygons or all the faces in the
model and after that we have to enable
the show normals option you can see that
the normals indicators that are these
blue lines they're much bigger than what
they supposed to be so here in this
scale we have to set a very small number
0.1 or 0.01 should be enough once you
are done resizing the normals indicator
don't forget to disable the show normals
option and to disable the polygon
selector icon as well just by clicking
on the polygon icon
again our 3D model still has some
Sharpie edges so let's apply some
smoothing to the surface of this model
and for smoothing our model we just have
to go back in the modify tab activating
again the polygon selector in the
editable mesh modifier and after we
select again all the faces in the model
we just have to go down in this window
and press the auto smooth
button our model now is fixed and smooth
and now we can apply the textures to
this model in the previous video of this
tutorial in the part one I have shown
you how to extract the textures now
let's apply to this model all the
textures that we have extracted before
so the textures that we have extracted
before in the first part of this
tutorial are separated in different
files each file has the textures for one
part of this model there is one texture
for Leon's face one texture for Leon's
hair one texture for his jacket one
texture for his gun and so on so what
I'm going to do here is to split this
model in different objects so I will
select some parts of this model and I
will detach this part making a new
object and each new object that I will
create will belong to one of these
texture files so in the end I'm going to
have one object for Leon's face one
object for Leon's hair one object for
the gun and I will apply a different
texture for each one of these new
objects so how I'm going to do this so
let's go back to the editable mesh
modifier but this time let's enable the
element selector and let's select all
the elements or faces in the 3D model
that belong to one texture file in this
case I'm selecting his face to add
multiple elements to the same selection
we can hold the control button while we
are selecting the elements if you want
to remove elements from the selection
you can hold the alt button and click in
the elements that you want to remove all
the selected elements are shown in red
and all the unselected elements are
shown in
white now that I have selected all the
elements that belong to the face texture
I'm going to create a new object from
the selected elements and for doing this
you just have to click in detach in here
we have to select a name of the new
object that will be created from these
selected elements now that we have
created a new object that matches to one
of our texture files let's apply this
texture to our new object and for doing
this I will select the object that I
have just created and then I'll click in
the material editor and here I'm going
to drag a standard material to our
material viewport you just have to drag
and drop it and after that I have to
drag a bit map material in the same way
that I did for the standard material
just drag and drop when I Dro this bit
map material in the material viewport
3ds Max is going to ask me what texture
file I want to add and I'm going to
select the texture file that has Leon's
face which is the texture that matches
to the object that I have just created
after that I have to go here in this
connector from the bigmat texture and I
have to drag this connector to its
destination that is the diffuse color
property of the standard material after
that we have to double click in the name
of the material so it becomes selected
when the material is selected it has
these Dash lines around it after that we
have to click in the assigned material
to selection button and for showing the
texture in our viewport we have to click
in this button called show shaded
material in viewport so this is how you
apply textures to your model you have to
repeat exactly the same method for each
part of the model that belongs to a
different texture so in the end we're
going to have multiple objects for this
model and each different object will
match to a different texture file since
this method is exactly the same for
every single texture for every part of
this model I would just skip forward so
this tutorial doesn't get too repetitive
if the textur get distorted or if they
just don't show up in the model this
means that maybe the texture map of the
model got corrupted The Only Solution in
this case is is to create a texture map
from scratch this problem is not very
common but if you want to learn how to
create texture maps from scratch just
let me know in the comments and I'll
make a special tutorial just focusing on
this problem
[Music]
so now let's make some final adjustments
to our 3D model it feels like this model
is still a little bit skewed or
distorted in the Y AIS so we're going to
fix this problem by making a skew
modifier but before applying this
modifier we have to go over all the
objects that we created and we have to
make sure that there is no element
selector enabled if there is any element
or polygon selector enabled we're going
to have problems when trying to fix the
distortions in our model now let's
select all our objects and let's group
them for grouping these objects together
after we select all of them we just have
to go here in the group menu and and
then we click in group now that we
grouped all these objects every time
that we apply one modifier to the root
of this group all the other objects that
belong to the same group will have the
same modifier applied to each one of
them so it's much easier to work in a
group like this when we have to apply
multiple modifiers in several objects so
having our group selected we're going to
go to the mod modify Tab and we're going
to add a skew modifier to fix the
distortions in our model here we have to
select in which AIS or which dimension
is the Distortion usually the Distortion
of models extracted from PlayStation 2
emulators will be in the Y AIS or the
horizontal axis depending on the level
of distortion of your model you may try
different numbers here for me an amount
of 15 and the direction or angle of
distortion of 100 or 90 for example
seems to be enough for fixing the
problem of this
model and here is the 3D model of Leon
from the Resident Evil 4 game from
PlayStation 2 extracted using text mod
and the
pcsx2 emulator after a lot of fixing
refining smoothing now we have our final
polished mod model here I try to show
all the techniques as simple as possible
but you can try as many parameters as
you like to refine your 3D model and
make it look even better so I hope this
tutorial was useful for you please don't
forget to give a like and to subscribe
to this channel to receive new tutorials
and please don't forget to share this
video in your social media so I see you
in the next tutorial bye-bye
n